Elementary School Entrance Ceremony
Okay?
Um...
Hi...
It's all blurry.
Rin-chan, Kouki, stand
next to each other!
Okay!
Kouki-kun!
Say "cheese"!
Next, I'll take a photo of you
with Rin-chan, Daikichi-san.
Nah, I don't need a shot of myself.
You have to! She'll grow
up before you know it.
So you have to keep a record of it!
Sure.
Daikichi-san, your
expression is stiff...
I dunno about tomorrow.
It's different than a sacrifice. Something's off.
I don't think it's like some penalty game.
So, why? I don't get it at all.
I'm a little bit unsatisfied, but your presence
right now is more than just important.
There's no such thing in this world
as something never-ending.
Crying isn't painful, it's love's sweet drops, sweet drops!
I want to keep dreaming forever, ya know?
I want to be more kind, ya know?
As long as I’m with you, I’m happy.
Girls sure are strong, ya know?
But sometimes we're weak, ya know?
Our wish is to be happy, happy, happy!
And those days will be happy, too!
Just wanna make you happy!
Again?!
Rin! How many times have I told
you not to go wandering off?!
Uh-huh...
You're a big girl now, so shape up!
Don't give me, "Uh-huh"!
Daikichi, can we buy this for a snack?
A snack?!
Well, it looked good...
Haven't you ever had cereal before?
Uh-uh.
Maybe it's too much for me?
No, I don't mind buying it...
But that's the kind of thing
you have for breakfast.
It's okay to eat sweets with rice?
Mmm... How do I put this?
It looks like sweets...
But you can have it as a meal.
You put milk on it...
Huh...
Why don't you have it
for breakfast tomorrow?
Yeah! I will.
Are you gonna have it too, Daikichi?
Nah. It doesn't fill me up..
Put your cereal in here.
Okay!
Daikichi, you stink at that...
I'm losing the oils in my hand...
You're like Grandpa!
Oh, shut up!
Then I'll watch you do it!
Daikichi, there are cherry blossoms
over there, so let's go home this way.
Sure.
They're blooming all over the place!
Because it's warm out.
Huge, isn't it?
They're in full bloom.
Since you're just starting
elementary school,
what do you say we plant
something to commemorate it?
Commemorate?
It's kind of like a remembrance.
Every year, both you and
the tree would get bigger.
Huh...
You know, I have my own tree.
At home?
By my parents' house.
When I was born, they planted
a fragrant olive tree.
For Kazumi, they planted
a tea olive tree.
"Fragrant olive tree", that's
the one that smells good?
That's right.
I don't know the "tea olive tree".
Let's see, the tea olive tree has some
plain flowers and not much of a smell...
That's why Kazumi used to say,
"It's not fair you get the
only one that smells nice!"
And she'd tear off the
flowers from my olive tree.
When I told her that I'd trade, she
said, "I don't want any hand-me-down!"
Huh? That's a bad memory,
so why am I thinking about
doing the same thing?
But if we're gonna do it,
I think it'd be more fun
to make it a pretty flower or
something that blooms, you know?
Or a fruit you can eat...
I wanna do a loquat!
A loquat?
Yeah, a loquat!
I had loquat seeds from before.
You plant the seeds?
I can eat as many loquats as I want!
That's if they actually grow.
Actually, I was thinking of planting a
tree that's about as tall as you, Rin.
I can't plant the loquat seeds?
It takes longer for a tree to get big,
compared to morning
glories and the like...
It's like that expression.
"It takes 3 years for peaches
and chestnuts to bear fruit...
Note : Proverb meaning
"Your actions often take time to bear fruit."
...and persimmons take eight"!
You really are Grandpa's
girl, aren't you?
How long for loquats?
I don't know, but what if
it takes like 10 years?
I can wait.
By that time, you'll probably be
more interested in fancy sweets.
I can't imagine it...
Daikichi, hurry up!
If we don't hurry, it'll be a
long time before we can eat them!
Yeah, yeah...
Is this enough?
Yeah. If it's too deep, the
bud won't be able to come out.
I see.
You're Grandpa's girl
through and through...
I hope the bud comes up soon!
Yep...
Rin, do you know what a ninja is?
Yeah, Kouki-kun says
he's gonna be a ninja.
They say that ninjas jump
over a hemp plant every day,
so the plant gets bigger and bigger
and by the time it's full grown,
they're jumping at an incredible height.
Huh...
Why don't you try that with your loquat?
I will!
Like that.
Like that?
Uh-huh.
Hey, how high does a loquat tree get?
About as high as our roof?
I dunno... Well...
Yeah, that's probably about right...
Okay, let's go inside.
All right, after ten more times!
I wonder if it'll sprout tomorrow...
Probably not by tomorrow...
Did you remember everything?
Uh-huh.
My teacher said someone from home
has to check my schedule, too.
Pain in the butt...
They didn't do this when I was a kid.
You're right. It says, "Please confirm."
Words for Communication
Fun Arithmetic
A fire?
Police car, I believe...
A crime?
I dunno.
Daikichi, attach this
whistle to my satchel.
Rin...
If somebody you don't know
starts talking to you,
you blow on this to make a loud sound.
Yeah.
And then run to any house!
A store would be fine, too!
All right!
Rin! School!
Daikichi! Come on, get up!
I'm gonna be late!
Okay...
Thank you for the food
I'm about to eat...
Thank you for the food I'm about to eat!
You put milk on it.
Can I eat just a little
bit of it like this?
Yeah, I guess...
Pet dogs eat this kind of thing.
That's dog food!
It's only for dogs.
Really?
That's right!
Humans can't eat dog food!
Huh...
Don't look regretful about it!
Is it good?
Uh-huh. Tasty!
Rice balls are still number one, though.
Those rice balls are tough to beat.
Daikichi, your phone!
Yeah...
Good morning!
I'm sorry. Kouki was so
enthusiastic, he rushed out!
Oh, that's okay.
No problem.
Right...
Kouki-kun's here!
He's here.
What's up?
Kouki-kun, you've got
burrs all over you!
What animal trail did
you take to get here?!
I'm not an animal!
And what's with your hair?
Rin, go get a comb.
Okay!
Jeez, your satchel is
scratched up now...
And I bet you scraped that stick across
people's walls too, didn't you?
Are you psychic?!
I can easily tell that kind of thing!
Is it because you did the same thing
when you were little, Daikichi?
Rin, hurry up and get ready!
Okay!
What's that look for?
See you later!
Hold on a second!
You still have time...
What's wrong?!
Kouki-kun!
You're not supposed to blow
that unless something happens!
Kouki-kun!
Knock it off!
Quit blowing that thing!
When you really do need help,
nobody's gonna come running!
Got it?
Then go ahead.
See you later!
Watch out for cars!
Okay!
Kouki-kun!
Let's take this way!
We're not supposed to go out of our way.
This isn't going out of
our way. It's a short cut!
I hear that ninjas...
...always take paths like this!
Sheesh...
It zigzags!
Yeah, right?
Kouki-kun!
You're too slow!
There's no point then to the short cut!
That's not what you do!
Kouki-kun...
That kid's hopeless...
I know, right?
Well, I guess it's...
Really, almost all boys are like that.
Daikichi...
The only ninja training I condone
is jumping over the loquat, right?
Right!
Oh, that loquat's a school
entrance commemoration, right?
Yeah.
But your olive tree is a remembrance
from when you were born,
so it's a little different, right?
Maybe I don't have anything
like a fragrant olive tree...
You're a sharp girl...
Did that mom of hers
plant a tree or anything?
Or maybe there's one at Grandpa's house.
Yeah, Grandpa might've...
But you don't know anything
about one there, do you?
No.
And Grandpa's gone...
If I don't know about
it, no one does, right?
I never should've told her
about the olive tree...
Daikichi! You've got your
elbow on the table again!
Right. Sorry...
Shit...
I didn't think we'd be meeting again.
I had the exact same thought.
This is from her school
entrance ceremony.
Thank you...
A tree for Rin?
There is one! There was one!
There is?!
Um... I think there was.
Why are you so iffy about it?
Because Souichi-san is
the one who planted it...
Grandpa did...
I'd like to transfer
that tree to my place.
What kind of tree is it?
A small one...
No, I mean what type, if you know...
And the location...
Mmm, it's still small...
And the branches are thin...
It's here.
You are a mangaka, yes?
Drawing maps isn't my job!
Which way is north?
North?
The sun rises in the west, so...
The opposite! It rises in the east!
Never mind directions.
Just please draw the street
that's in front of the house.
Oh, yeah... Duh.
Well, I've got work to do, so excuse me.
Thank you for the ice cream.
Sorry to bother you
when you're so busy...
I wonder if I did have my own tree...
I'm sure Grandpa planted
something for you, Rin-chan.
That's what my instinct tells me.
And even if there isn't, I think
you could plant another tree
to commemorate you starting
elementary school.
A tree that's six years old.
Yeah...
Do you want to see Daikichi's tree?
Yeah, I wanna see it!
It's big, isn't it?!
That's because it's 30 years
old, just like Daikichi.
It got big, and Daikichi, too...
It's a fragrant olive, right?
That's right. You know your trees.
Daikichi told me.
This one is Kazumi's tree.
Tea olive?
Right...
Do you remember the big
tree in Grandpa's backyard?
Oh, that one...
That's my tree, a tea olive.
Huh...
Huh? This tree...
Grandpa planted it when I was born.
You have the same tree
as Kazumi-chan, huh?
That's right.
When I was a child, I always
compared my height to it.
I loved it, which is why I
continued the tradition here.
Was that a tea olive tree?
Did Daikichi compare his
height with his tree, too?
Of course!
Long before that day we first met...
Daikichi, is that...
It has the same leaves!
It's a six-year-old
fragrant olive tree...
The same as mine.
This'll do.
Shoot!
What?
It's too late to jump
over this one, isn't it?
I don't think I could even do it...
And we weren't even aware Rin existed
until six months ago, you know?
I know...
Daikichi! The train's gonna leave!
Coming!
Well...
I'll see you off.
But...
long before that day we first met,
we were all walking
along a similar course.
A sunny early Sunday afternoon
Let's go somewhere today
It's the same road I'm used to traveling
But I can see it sparkling so bright
With the sun shining down its warmth
And you here by my side...
I'm already high, high, high
I feel like dashing out
Sing, la, la, la
My voice out to forever
I'm already high, high, high
Ride the dancing wind
Sing, la, la, la
My voice springs up
Daikichi!
What's wrong?!
What happened?!
There's a strange old man outside!
Kouki-kun...
No... That man is...
What?!
Daikichi, he's not...
Where is he?!
Enough! Both of you, listen to me!
That's our neighbor, Matsui-san!
Don't call him a "strange old man"!
I'm sorry...
I'm... sor...ry...
I'm the one who should apologize.
Apparently, my sudden
greeting frightened him.
Sorry about that.
No, no, he was incredibly rude.
Well, be careful going to school.
See you later!
Thank you.
When you ran away, you
dragged Rin along with you.
But Kouki-kun made a mistake...
If Kouki's with you, I feel
a little more reassured.
Just a little?!
Yeah, just a little!
You're still a runt!
I'm not a runt!
We're gonna be late...